<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: meetup | Elcodi blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://elcodi-blog.github.io/blog/categories/meetup/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://elcodi-blog.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2015-11-23T17:48:10+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://elcodi-blog.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Elcodi Team]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Suggest our next features]]></title>
    <link href="http://elcodi-blog.github.io/blog/2015/11/23/suggest-our-next-features/"/>
    <updated>2015-11-23T17:13:35+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://elcodi-blog.github.io/blog/2015/11/23/suggest-our-next-features</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>For sure some of you already know about
<a href="http://blog.elcodi.io/blog/2015/11/20/elcodi-online-meetup/">Elcodi&rsquo;s first online meetup</a>.
It will be next November 25th at 6:00pm GMT+1, and for joining us, you only have
to enter <a href="http://gitter.im/elcodi/elcodi">our gitter room</a>, say hello, and join
our discussion about Elcodi, Symfony and E-commerce.</p>

<p>One of the topics we&rsquo;ll talk about will be our roadmap. We&rsquo;ve configured it just
by thinking what features would be nice to have in the <del>future</del> present, but
Elcodi is a community-first project, so we would love to bring you some voice,
at least to help us deciding about what features we should put our effort the
next months.</p>

<blockquote><p>Of course, your voice is the most wanted voice in Elcodi. Make sure you really
say what you think, so we can improve day by day.</p></blockquote>

<p>For that, from today until the start of the meeting, you will be able to join
our room and show us your proposals. This wednesday we will vote each one, and
the most voted will be part of our <code>v1.3</code> roadmap, creating a group of
volunteers for that development.</p>

<h3>Propose a feature</h3>

<ul>
<li>Enter <a href="http://gitter.im/elcodi/elcodi">our gitter room</a></li>
<li>Say Hello! :)</li>
<li>Make a proposal</li>
</ul>


<h3>Vote the features</h3>

<ul>
<li>Enter <a href="http://gitter.im/elcodi/elcodi">our gitter room</a> next November 25th at
6:00pm GMT+1</li>
<li>Say hello! :)</li>
<li>Vote your more exciting features (before starting the meetup, you will have
the link for voting)</li>
<li>Join the development!</li>
<li>Enjoy as much as possible ;)</li>
</ul>


<p>We really look forward to see you all there!
By sharing this post you will really help us creating this community :)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Elcodi online meetup]]></title>
    <link href="http://elcodi-blog.github.io/blog/2015/11/20/elcodi-online-meetup/"/>
    <updated>2015-11-20T21:50:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://elcodi-blog.github.io/blog/2015/11/20/elcodi-online-meetup</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://elcodi.io">Elcodi</a> is growing so fast.</p>

<blockquote><p>Elcodi is an E-commerce platform based on Symfony components. Is composed by
some PHP Components, by some Symfony Bundles and by a Full-stack project based
on the Symfony Framework. A all-in-one E-commerce solution, splitted in
several isolated parts.</p></blockquote>

<p>We started this project two and a half years ago, and our community is getting
bigger day after day. That&rsquo;s great because the project grows as well as long as
more people start using it (more needs, more ideas, more contributions, more
fun).</p>

<p>We will start doing monthly meetings online in our
<a href="http://gitter.im/elcodi/elcodi">Gitter channel</a>. Right now, some people is
daily contributing to Elcodi and having some nice and constructive talks, but we
want to make it even bigger.</p>

<p>Our first monthly meeting will be next November 25th at 6:00pm GMT+1.
This meeting will be hosted by the core team of the project,
<a href="https://github.com/mmoreram">Marc Morera</a> and
<a href="https://github.com/EmanueleMinotto">Emanuele Minotto</a>.</p>

<h2>Agenda</h2>

<p>This meeting will be focused on creating some working groups for the next weeks.
Depending on the people attending at the meeting, we will create more or less
groups, focused on some parts of the application.</p>

<p>These are the points we will talk about.</p>

<ul>
<li>Tasks for next version <code>v1.1</code>.</li>
<li>Documentation update and revision.</li>
<li>Test coverage for <code>v1.1</code>.</li>
<li>Community action. How to make as many people as possible involved.</li>
</ul>


<h2>Attendees</h2>

<p>Maybe you&rsquo;re asking yourself if this meeting is for you.</p>

<p>Well, it depends on your interests. If your job is all about E-commerce, even if
your Symfony skills are no so good, then you should join us. You will have the
opportunity to share some time with really skilled people and to know the way we
have created this project.</p>

<p>If your interest is open source, join us as well. Elcodi is a young project,
focused on finding the right equilibrium between pragmatism and clean
architecture. We use Event-Driven Architecture and annotations at the same time.
Do you want to know why? What are our thoughts? Ask us :)</p>

<p>In other words, if you want to have a nice time with some really good people,
then you definitely should join us and say a big Hello!</p>

<p>Remember, next November 25th at&hellip;</p>

<ul>
<li>Mexico City, La Havana &ndash; 11:00am</li>
<li>London &ndash; 05:00pm</li>
<li>Barcelona, Paris, Warsaw &ndash; 06:00pm</li>
<li>Moscow &ndash; 08:00pm</li>
</ul>


<p>Looking forward to see you all there!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
