<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: symfony | Elcodi blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://elcodi-blog.github.io/blog/categories/symfony/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://elcodi-blog.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-08-12T10:16:21+02:00</updated>
  <id>http://elcodi-blog.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Elcodi Team]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Our roadmap]]></title>
    <link href="http://elcodi-blog.github.io/blog/2014/08/12/our-roadmap/"/>
    <updated>2014-08-12T09:55:48+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://elcodi-blog.github.io/blog/2014/08/12/our-roadmap</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h5>This is the second part of a <a href="/blog/2014/08/11/a-short-break-for-meditation/">previous post</a></h5>

<p>We can proudly state we have a lot to do in the following months.</p>

<p>Question is, what now? Maybe we are 1% done along our path, although &ldquo;done&rdquo; in our world sounds a bit odd since there is always room for improvement.
As long as our issue tracker list gets fed, we will stay hungry for enhancing our code.</p>

<h3>GeoBundle</h3>

<p>One of the most recurring challenges in e-commerce development is the modeling of geographic and administrative divisions. We will put our efforts in designing a simple yet extensible set of entities and relations as well as strategies to implement custom tree structures.</p>

<h3>Rule management</h3>

<p>Rule-based decision logic is ubiquitous in e-commerce applications. A few examples:</p>

<ul>
<li>Which discount coupon can be automatically applied upon entering the checkout process?</li>
<li>Can a particular discount code be applied?</li>
<li>Can two specific products be added to the same cart?</li>
<li>Can a specific product combination trigger a discount, an up-sell or a different offer?</li>
<li>When is it possible to use a specific carrier or payment method?</li>
</ul>


<p>Elcodi <a href="https://github.com/elcodi/rulebundle">RuleBundle</a> aims at solving these kinds of issue.</p>

<h3>Ports and Adapters</h3>

<p>We surely want to promote high-cohesion, loose-coupled software components. Right now we are halfway, as described in the <a href="/blog/2014/08/11/a-short-break-for-meditation/">previous post</a>, but we want to keep improving. A typical usage of P&amp;A would be to decouple Symfony bundles from other significant objects in the domain, or to be able to use Elcodi Cart component without depending on the CustomerBundle.</p>

<h3>Tests</h3>

<p>A great deal of credibility for an open source project is earned by instilling a thorough and sound test methodology. We assume that we&rsquo;ve been lacking on this specific subject, doing our homeworks halfway. This will be addressed both for Elcodi core repository and web applications (<a href="https://github.com/elcodi/bamboo-store">BambooStore</a> and <a href="https://github.com/elcodi/bamboo-admin">BambooAdmin</a>) by raising the coverage of unit and functional tests and start working with acceptance tests for the web apps.</p>

<p>We have not decided yet which toolset we will be using, surely one between <a href="http://docs.behat.org/">Behat3</a> and <a href="http://www.phpspec.net/">PHPSpec2</a>. As always, suggestions are more than welcome!</p>

<h3>PaymentSuite</h3>

<p>The <a href="http://github.com/PaymentSuite">PaymentSuite</a> was conceived and grown inside Elcodi.</p>

<p>It is a payment processing suite developed in Symfony2 which follows our vision of extensibility using adapters and dispatched events to give maximum flexibility to implementers and to decouple specific <code>Cart</code> or <code>Order</code> implementations. It promotes easy and sensible defaults for configurations.</p>

<p>We will take care of the project and will evolve it as the default payment platform. The <a href="http://bamboo.elcodi.com">BambooStore</a> is already using a dummy <a href="https://github.com/PaymentSuite/FreePaymentBundle">free payment</a> method.</p>

<h3>ShippingSuite</h3>

<p>We would like to follow a similar path as the PaymentSuite: a separated and parallel project that does not depend on Elcodi and that can be easy integrated in web applications. Same vision, same resilience philosophy: work with <code>Order</code> or <code>Carrier</code> as <em>adaptees</em>.</p>

<h3>Documentation</h3>

<p>Akin to the phisolophers' stone, sibling of the Holy Grail, the documentation is the most precious gemstone that an open source project should strive to shape. As Symfony2 author <a href="https://twitter.com/fabpot">@fabpot</a> once said, it is the most challenging part of any project.</p>

<p>We are working on the foundation of an <a href="http://elcodi.readthedocs.org">english documentation</a>, localized and translated version will follow later on. This is a list of topics that we will elaborate further:</p>

<ul>
<li>Implementation guidelines. General vision and coding philosophy, style and everything needed for developers wishing to contribute.</li>
<li>Customizations. Craft a project using only Elcodi core. Architectural constraints to keep in mind. Recipes and examples.</li>
<li>Core bundles documentation, including

<ul>
<li>Provisioned Model</li>
<li>Event system rationale and taxonomies</li>
<li>Services</li>
<li>Configuration</li>
<li>Controllers and extensions, where it may apply</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/elcodi/bamboo-store">Bamboo</a> <a href="https://github.com/elcodi/bamboo-admin">web applications</a> documentation for Symfony and front-end developers: the starting point to develop your e-commerce site.</li>
</ul>


<p>This is going to be an epic effort and the real main entrance to the project for the community. No matter the size of your codebase is, documentation is a key measure of a project success.</p>

<h2>Community</h2>

<p>If documentation should be our <em>diamond</em>, the community should be our <em>propellant</em>. A good community makes a project good.</p>

<p>We started as a small project and we know how demanding it can be to get involved and contribute to the development of an open source based product.</p>

<p>We will take special care of this particular topic, since motivating people and get them involved is essential for our vision: Elcodi was never mean to be a mere code repository, it is a group of visionary people with a clear view in their minds, working together to work out a specific problem.</p>

<p>Taking care of the code means caring for the people that make it possible for the code to be crafted. We are especially interested in helping those who want to learn, so we will soon arrange training and learning mechanisms, both for Symfony and Elcodi.</p>

<p>Get ready to be effective!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[A short break for meditation]]></title>
    <link href="http://elcodi-blog.github.io/blog/2014/08/11/a-short-break-for-meditation/"/>
    <updated>2014-08-11T09:05:38+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://elcodi-blog.github.io/blog/2014/08/11/a-short-break-for-meditation</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h5>Puedes encontrar la versión en castellano de este post <a href="/blog/2014/08/04/un-momento-para-reflexionar/">aqui</a>.</h5>

<p>Some of you already know Elcodi, a suite of components built on Symfony2 and Doctrine, aiming to provide maximum flexibility and soundness to e-commerce projects.</p>

<p>We believe that coding should always be entertaining and fun.</p>

<p>This has been our main mission since the beginning and as every ambitious goal you cannot forget that along the journey you might discover an equally important path.</p>

<p>I think that we reached the point where it is important to take a breath, so that in the following days we will publish some posts regarding our views and what we&rsquo;ve been learning, where we will talk about what we have developed so far, our expectations and how we would like to drive the development of each part of the project in the following months.</p>

<h1>The path so far</h1>

<p>Elcodi was born a few months ago in a nice workplace located in Barcelona, Spain. We started designing the platform at the beginning of the year, developed and refactored the pieces up the present day where in my opinion we reached a fairly good balanced point, which is the growing seed of our natural direction.</p>

<h3>ProductBundle, AttributeBundle</h3>

<p>Those components are the home for everything regarding products, categories, manufacturers. Product attribute and options were added in a separate bundle and are the dimensions for working in the product variants space, which is one of the latest features developed and is a required trait for almost every e-commerce software implementation.</p>

<p>Multi-category is also supported for products.</p>

<h3>UserBundle</h3>

<p>Contains the models and tools necessary for working with front-end customers or back-end administrators. A basic authentication &amp; authorization definition was also added, exploiting Symfony Security component.</p>

<h3>CartBundle</h3>

<p>It handles the purchase process, carts and orders. Undoubtedly one of the core pillars of any e-commerce, it has been designed to be simple to get a grasp of and to be overridden almost completely by custom logic. You can read about its internal in the <a href="http://elcodi.readthedocs.org/en/latest/bundles/CartBundle/index.html">official documentation</a>.
Point-in-time snapshots of order states or cart to order transitions are examples of what is provided in CartBundle core services default implementation.</p>

<h3>GeoBundle</h3>

<p>Basic building block for a complete hierarchical aggregation of administrative entities. Due to lack of time, at the present day only <code>Country</code> is modeled as a mapped class, leaving <code>State</code>, <code>Province</code> or <code>City</code> as text fields.</p>

<h3>MediaBundle</h3>

<p>Allows the storage-agnostic handling of media files, such as images. It also controls image resizing and consolidates HTTP headers for media files.</p>

<p>Other bundles are:</p>

<ul>
<li>BannerBundle</li>
<li>LanguageBundle</li>
<li>CurrencyBundle</li>
<li>MenuBundle</li>
<li>NewsletterBundle</li>
<li>ReferralProgramBundle</li>
<li>RuleBundle</li>
</ul>


<h3>BambooStore</h3>

<p>We developed a prototype of a front-end store, the <a href="http://bamboo.elcodi.com/">Bamboo</a>. It is a showcase of Elcodi core features and uses <a href="https://github.com/PaymentSuite">PaymentSuite</a> <a href="https://github.com/PaymentSuite/FreePaymentBundle">FreePaymentBundle</a> as payment method.</p>

<h3>BambooAdmin</h3>

<p>Something we just published. An initial release of a <a href="https://github.com/elcodi/bamboo-admin">backoffice application</a>, providing basic features yet usable. Likewise Elcodi core and the Bamboo frontend, it will be in constant development. Versions and releases of the three projects will stay synchronized, not to break dependencies.</p>

<h3>Implementation</h3>

<p>We know that unfortunately, at least at this stage, our design choices and implementation cannot satisfy everyone. Trying to do it would require a massive effort and can lead to a loss of focus and direction. We prefer stick with our vision despite the errors we would make.</p>

<p>A question we are frequently asked is why we are coupling with Symfony and Doctrine: this is a trade-off we had to settle for trying to maximize acceptance from both developers and end users by enforcing clean, coherent, structured and documented code.</p>

<p>Right now we don&rsquo;t think it is feasable to assemble more layers of indirection to achieve this decoupling. The goal is to involve the Symfony community and work on the feedbacks we will receive from developers who want to build applications with Elcodi. Mind you that Symfony decoupling <em>is</em> possible, since we are trying to follow the <strong>SOLID</strong> path, but the eternal struggle between being different and effective flows to a point of balance that surely will benefit both the project and our users.</p>

<p>Cheers!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Objetivos]]></title>
    <link href="http://elcodi-blog.github.io/blog/2014/08/06/objetivos/"/>
    <updated>2014-08-06T12:12:19+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://elcodi-blog.github.io/blog/2014/08/06/objetivos</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>Este post es la continuación de dos posts anteriores</h2>

<ul>
<li><a href="/blog/2014/08/04/un-momento-para-reflexionar/">Un momento para reflexionar</a>.</li>
<li><a href="/blog/2014/08/05/nuestro-roadmap/">Nuestro roadmap</a>.</li>
</ul>


<p>A corto plazo, queremos llegar a una primera versión estable para la comunidad.
Esta semana hemos puesto la primera piedra de muchas, pero es importante
establecer reglas y procedimientos cuando pondremos las siguientes.</p>

<p>Tenemos un pequeño set de <a href="https://github.com/elcodi/elcodi/milestones">milestones</a>
para tener una pequeña guía de acción (como veis, esta semana tenemos la release
de la versión 0.3)</p>

<p>```
Version 0.3</p>

<pre><code>- Closed 3 days ago
- 100% complete  0 open  11 closed
</code></pre>

<p>Version 0.4</p>

<pre><code>- Due by August 15, 2014
- 0% complete  0 open  0 closed
</code></pre>

<p>Version 0.5</p>

<pre><code>- Due by August 29, 2014
- 17% complete  5 open  1 closed
</code></pre>

<p>Version 0.6</p>

<pre><code>- Due by September 11, 2014
- 0% complete  2 open  0 closed
</code></pre>

<p>```</p>

<p>Esto significa que vamos a trabajar en mejorar lo que tenemos, sin desarrollar
más lógica de negocio hasta que no tengamos algo un poco más estable, así como
la comunicación para que la gente interesada tenga claro los timings y tengan
más visibilidad a la hora de implementar con Elcodi.</p>

<p>Por ahora nos nos vamos a preocupar demasiado de los BC Breaks. Hay una
<a href="https://github.com/elcodi/elcodi/issues/34">issue</a> abierta para cerrar API,
pero como bien dice <a href="">@hacfi</a> no es especialmente importante en este intervalo
tan enfocado al desarrollo de nuevas funcionalidades. Creemos que cumplir con
un semantic version ahora mismo solo limitaría la arquitectura en muchos
aspectos.</p>

<p>Hasta la versión 1.0 no habrá <em>semantic version</em>.</p>

<p>Otro objetivo es, una vez llegado a la primera versión estable, abrir ya el
market. Dado que a medida que pasa el tiempo la api va cambiando menos, creemos
que no falta demasiado para poder llegar a este punto.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Nuestro roadmap]]></title>
    <link href="http://elcodi-blog.github.io/blog/2014/08/05/nuestro-roadmap/"/>
    <updated>2014-08-05T12:46:22+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://elcodi-blog.github.io/blog/2014/08/05/nuestro-roadmap</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h5>Este post es la continuación de <a href="/blog/2014/08/04/un-momento-para-reflexionar/">uno anterior</a>.</h5>

<p>Podemos decir con orgullos que tenemos proyecto por mucho tiempo.</p>

<p>La pregunta es&hellip; ¿y ahora qué? Pues bueno, ahora solo hemos andado un uno por
ciento del camino al completo (Creo que la palabra &ldquo;completo&rdquo; es algo
inexistente en nuestro ámbito&hellip; siempre hay cosas que hacer y mejorar&hellip;).
Almenos, y mientras nuestra lista de Issues y Features no esté vacía, tenemos
ganas de mejorar nuestro repositorio. Aquí algunas cosas importantes.</p>

<h3>GeoBundle</h3>

<p>Consideramos que es uno de los problemas más trabajados en todas las empresas
ecommerce, tener un buen sistema geográfico. Tenerlo implica poder segmentar
mucho mejor y cotejar los datos, para sacar buenas métricas y así mejorar la
experiencia de usuario.</p>

<p>Queremos trabajar en un completo sistema relacional de entidades, de tal forma
que, con comandos simples se puedan customizar y poblar tablas enteras.</p>

<h3>Gestión de Reglas</h3>

<p>Una parte interesante del proyecto es la utilización de reglas en todo el
modelo. Por ejemplo.</p>

<ul>
<li>¿Cuando se aplica un cupón automático de cart?</li>
<li>¿Cuando es posible aplicar un cupón cuando se aplica?</li>
<li>¿Cuando es posible mezclar dos productos?</li>
<li>¿Cuando se puede utilizar un Carrier o un método de pago?</li>
</ul>


<p>Podemos solucionar de una forma muy natural y intruitiva todas estas necesidades
con un buen sistema de reglas.</p>

<h3>Ports and Adapters</h3>

<p>Una de las cosas que mas nos preocupa es el poder trabajar con los componentes
de forma desacoplada. Creo que estamos enmedio del camino, por lo que queremos
aprender como hacerlo mejor. Los &ldquo;Ports and Adapters&rdquo; es una forma de trabajar
con implementaciones propias del componente, implementando adapters para las
implementaciones externas. De esta forma, podemos decir que un Cart tiene un
Customer, sin tener la necesidad de trabajar con CustomerBundle.</p>

<p>Trabajaremos en ello. Seguro.</p>

<h3>Tests</h3>

<p>Hemos hecho los deberes a medias, lo reconocemos, y dado que sabemos que parte
de la confianza de un proyecto open source se genera con la cantidad y,
importante, la calidad de sus tests, vamos a trabajar para que ambas cosas
crezcan a la vez, tanto en los bundles de Elcodi como en los proyectos
BambooStore y BambooAdmin.</p>

<p>Trabajaremos en las baterías de Tests unitarios y funcionales, como hemos hecho
hasta ahora, incluso incrementando notablemente el nivel, y en las baterias
de tests de comportamiento en las Bamboo.</p>

<p>No tenemos muy claro que proyectos utilizar para tales fines. Tenemos en mente
Behat3 y PHPSPec2, así que toda opinión sobre el tema serás más que bienvenida!</p>

<h3>PaymentSuite</h3>

<p>El proyecto <a href="http://github.com/PaymentSuite">PaymentSuite</a> nació dentro de
Elcodi.</p>

<p>Es un repositorio de pagos implementado en Symfony2, preparado para trabajar
100% sobre una capa de eventos. Esta capa te permite poder abstraer la
implementación del Cart o del Order, así como la implementación del método de
pago, por lo que la activación o desactivación de los métodos de pago se hacen
triviales, solo activando y configurando.</p>

<p>Desde Elcodi vamos a trabajar en el proyecto.</p>

<h3>ShippingSuite</h3>

<p>Queremos hacer lo mismo que con PaymentSuite. Un proyecto que trabaje sobre la
capa de eventos de Symfony y abstraiga, tanto el Order como la implementación
del Carrier.</p>

<p>Con los pagos nos ha funcionado a la perfección, así que seguro que vamos a
seguir el mismo camino para esta necesidad.</p>

<h3>Documentación</h3>

<p>El diamante que buscar, encontrar, limpiar y tallar. La famosa documentación.
Consideramos que es la verdadera joya de la corona, como dijo una vez @fabpot,
la documentación es la parte más complicada del proyecto, y lo sabemos.</p>

<p>Vamos a trabajar para hacer una buena documentación en inglés, así como la
traducción en el máximo de idiomas posibles.</p>

<ul>
<li>Documentación de implementación. Estilos que hemos seguido, así como puntos
importantes a conocer para los contribuidores.</li>
<li>Documentación de customización. En realidad consistirá más en un conjunto de
recetas.</li>
<li>Patrones que hemos utilizado y sus razones de ser</li>
<li>Documentación por Bundle.</li>
<li>Modelo</li>
<li>Capa de eventos (dispatchers y listeners)</li>
<li>Capa de servicio</li>
<li>Capa de extensiones de Twig</li>
<li>Capa de configuración</li>
<li>Capa de controlador (en el caso de las implementaciones de front y back)</li>
<li>Documentación de front. Que necesita un frontend para realizar
implementaciones propias de frontal</li>
</ul>


<p>Sabemos que no será tarea fácil, pero al menos estamos seguros que parte del
éxito de cualquier proyecto, por pequeño que sea, es la capacidad de documentar
que pueda llegar a tener, así como lo acogedor que pueda llegar a ser el entorno
del proyecto.</p>

<h3>Comunidad</h3>

<p>Si la documentación es nuestro diamante, la comunidad es nuestro carburante. Una
buena comunidad hace el buen proyecto.</p>

<p>Nacimos como un pequeño proyecto en Symfony y sabemos lo complicado y agresivo
que puede llegar a ser, para una persona no acostumbrada a estar en entornos
tan estrictos, el hecho de participar y involucrarse en el desarrollo de una
tecnología.</p>

<p>Pues bien, como lo hemos vivido y sabemos que es, en parte, la clave de nuestro
éxito, vamos a tratar este punto con especial interés y cariño. Elcodi no es tan
solo un código en un repositorio, es un conjunto de personas con una idea clara
en la cabeza y con la ilusión de trabajar juntas para solucionar un problema.</p>

<p>Es por esto que si queremos cuidar el código al máximo, debemos cuidar a las
personas que hacen posible que el código exista. Tenemos mucho interés en que la
gente que quiera aprender, lo haga, así que vamos a diseñar sistemas de learning
y de formación, tanto en Symfony como en Elcodi, para que la gente que quiera
participar con nosotros, lo pueda hacer con el máximo nivel posible.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Un momento para reflexionar]]></title>
    <link href="http://elcodi-blog.github.io/blog/2014/08/04/un-momento-para-reflexionar/"/>
    <updated>2014-08-04T13:53:28+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://elcodi-blog.github.io/blog/2014/08/04/un-momento-para-reflexionar</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h5>You can find the english version of this post on <a href="/blog/2014/08/11/a-short-break-for-meditation/">A short break for meditation</a>.</h5>

<p>Algunos de vosotros ya conocéis Elcodi. Una serie de componentes hechos desde 0
con componentes de Symfony2 y Doctrine2, especialmente diseñados para
proporcionar el máximo de flexibilidad y de robustez a los proyectos Ecommerce.</p>

<p>Programar debe ser siempre un placer.</p>

<p>Este es nuestro objetivo desde el principio, y como todos los objetivos, no hay
eue olvidar que, hasta llegar a ellos, hay un camino no menos importante.</p>

<p>Creo que hemos llegado a un punto de inflexión donde es importante detenerse,
así que durante los próximos dias vamos a sacar una serie de posts referentes a
nuestra reflexiones donde pondremos sobre la mesa temas importantes como lo que
tenemos hecho hasta ahora, nuestra espectativas, y como vamos a hacer cada
trozo del proyecto durante los próximos meses.</p>

<h1>El camino hasta ahora</h1>

<p>Elcodi empezó hace unos meses en una bonita oficina de Barcelona. Nuestro
departamento técnico empezó a diseñar el proyecto a principios de año y hasta
ahora, y entre unos cuantos refáctorings interesantes, llegamos a un punto de
equilibrio, en mi opinión, bastante bueno, semilla de nuestra dirección actual.</p>

<p>Hasta ahora hemos trabajado sobretodo en funcionalidades básicas de interés
común en cuanto a ecommerce se refiere.</p>

<h3>ProductBundle, AttributeBundle</h3>

<p>Todo lo referente al Producto, Categoría y Marca. El Bundle tiene definido tanto
el modelo como una serie de herramientas para trabajar con él. Una de las
últimas incorporacion ha sido la implementación de multiproducto, muy útil en
la mayoría de sites ecommerce de hoy en día.</p>

<p>También soporta multicategoría.</p>

<h3>UserBundle</h3>

<p>Modelo y herramientas para trabajar tanto con Customer como con Administradores
para el Backoffice. También se ha creado una definición básica de autenticación
y de autentificación utilizando el ya conocido Secure de Symfony.</p>

<h3>CartBundle</h3>

<p>Gestor de Carts y Orders. Una de las partes troncales de todo ecommerce viene
en un formato bastante sencillo, diseñado para poder ser sobreescrito
practicamente en su totalidad. Se ha implementado seguimiento de Orders mediante
histórico de estados, así las herramientas de transformación de Cart a Order.</p>

<h3>CouponBundle</h3>

<p>Definición del modelo de cupón. Este bundle está particularmente desacoplado de
todos los demás, por lo que solo tiene dependencia con <code>core-bundle</code> y con
<code>currency-bundle</code>. Si se quiere trabajar con el CartBundle de Elcodi, también
se ha creado CartCouponBundle, un <strong>nexo</strong> entre ambos modelos que, a partir
de los eventos del EventDispatcher, se encarga del comportamiento asociado a los
cupones del cart.</p>

<h3>GeoBundle</h3>

<p>Semilla para toda la definición y gestión de un modelo geográfico completo. Por
ahora, y dado que no hemos dedicado demasiado tiempo a esta parte, solo tenemos
Country como entidad, dejando como campos abiertos los demás campos como
<code>Region</code>, <code>City</code> y <code>Postalcode</code></p>

<p>Otros Bundles más son</p>

<ul>
<li>BannerBundle</li>
<li>LanguageBundle</li>
<li>CurrencyBundle</li>
<li>MediaBundle</li>
<li>MenuBundle</li>
<li>NewsletterBundle</li>
<li>ReferralProgramBundle</li>
<li>RuleBundle</li>
</ul>


<h3>BambooStore</h3>

<p>Hemos desarrollado una primera fase de un Store. Por ahora con camisetas muy
chulas y utilizando el
<a href="https://github.com/PaymentSuite/FreePaymentBundle">FreePaymentBundle</a> de
PaymentSuite.</p>

<p>Es una versión muy simple, pero seguro muy útil como punto de partida para
muchos departamentos técnicos</p>

<h3>BambooAdmin</h3>

<p>Algo nuevo. Hemos estado trabajando el último mes en una base (muy simple y algo
incompleta) de un administrador. Estará en constrante desarrollo (junto con
el store y el core, yendo de la mano en cuanto a versiones).</p>

<h3>Implementación</h3>

<p>Sabemos que nuestra implementación no dejará a todo el mundo contento, y la
verdad no queremos que sea así. Consideramos que dejar a todos el mundo contento
es algo imposible, y lo que terminas teniendo es un producto sin ningún tipo de
identidad, por lo que nosotros preferimos definir bien nuestra dirección, y
desarrollar a pesar de los errores que podamos cometer.</p>

<p>Hemos recibido preguntas muy positivas del porqué estamos acoplándonos al
framework Symfony y al ORM de Doctrine2. Pues bien, lo hacemos porque nuestro
objetivo es realmente llegar a ser lo máximo útiles posible, tanto para el
desarrollador como para el usuario final, y la única forma de que sea así es
tratar con código mantenible, comprensible, documentado y estructurado.</p>

<p>En esta fase del proyecto no creemos que valga la pena añadir mas capas de
indirección para realizar esta desvinculación. El objetivo ahora mismo es
intentar involucrar la comunidad Symfony y recibir feedback de desarrolladores
que intenten montar algo con Elcodi.</p>

<p>En la busca de un tradeoff entre hacer las cosas lo máximo de bien posible, y
tratar de ser algo diferentes a los demás, hemos consideramos que ambas
relaciones son y serán buenas para el proyecto, así como para los
desarrolladores que decidan trabajar sobre él.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
