<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: A week of Elcodi | Elcodi blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://elcodi-blog.github.io/blog/categories/a-week-of-elcodi/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://elcodi-blog.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2015-04-20T15:09:19+02:00</updated>
  <id>http://elcodi-blog.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Elcodi Team]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Week of Elcodi #5 (24/11 - 08/12)]]></title>
    <link href="http://elcodi-blog.github.io/blog/2014/12/11/a-week-of-elcodi-number-5/"/>
    <updated>2014-12-11T20:15:24+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://elcodi-blog.github.io/blog/2014/12/11/a-week-of-elcodi-number-5</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Hi there! These two weeks have been full of work, with our talk in <a href="http://madrid2014.symfony.com">SymfonyCon</a> being the highlight. We&rsquo;re working on a post explaining the experience but, in short, it was amazing to present Elcodi to the people in the Symfony community. Stay tuned!</p>

<p>Meanwhile, on this side of the keyboard, we&rsquo;ve been doing some things also, such as resume the implementation of our <code>StateTransitionMachine</code>, previously known as <code>StateMachine</code>, and polishing some details.</p>

<p>Besides, we wanted to implement an entity translator completely decoupled of our entities, because we think that the most important part of an e-commerce project is the model. So we worked on it for a while and now the <a href="https://github.com/elcodi/elcodi/pull/382">Translator component</a> is born. You&rsquo;re welcome to comment and collaborate on the implementation.</p>

<p>To persist the settings for each shop, we are working on a <a href="https://github.com/elcodi/elcodi/pull/383">dynamic configuration component</a> useful for storing simple values. As usual, it comes with adapters so that any backend storage can be supported.</p>

<p>From the viewpoint of desing, we want a more agile, easy and intuitive admin experience, so we&rsquo;re checking and improving the UX of Elcodi Admin&rsquo;s interface. First adjustments include some improvements about navigation, and an early approach to the first-time experience, something that we will look in depth in the next week.</p>

<p>Also we&rsquo;re putting together our <a href="https://github.com/elcodi/elcodi/pull/378">new Page component</a> to be as generic as possible, but user-friendly too. This includes developers: we are making great efforts to provide a better DX (Developer eXperience), so feel free to drop by our <a href="https://gitter.im/elcodi/elcodi">gitter</a> and ask your own questions. We&rsquo;ll be glad to help you. ;)</p>

<p>See you next week!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[A week of Elcodi #4 (17/11 - 24/11)]]></title>
    <link href="http://elcodi-blog.github.io/blog/2014/11/25/a-week-of-elcodi-number-4/"/>
    <updated>2014-11-25T12:39:32+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://elcodi-blog.github.io/blog/2014/11/25/a-week-of-elcodi-number-4</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Last few days were kind of crazy at Elcodi, with @alch <a href="http://madrid2014.symfony.com/speakers#session-1399">leaving the slides ready for our speak at the #SymfonyCon</a>, @mmoreram <a href="http://mmoreram.com/blog/2014/11/25/symfony-walk-ends">walking the #SymfonyWalk</a> and @xphere <a href="https://github.com/elcodi/elcodi">annoying in our GitHub repository</a> and <a href="http://blog.elcodi.io/blog/categories/one-section-one-component">writing about Symfony Components</a>.</p>

<p>But this madness is great, trust me! We&rsquo;ll reach a milestone in our path with the forthcoming #SymfonyCon, and we&rsquo;re proud and happy to have the opportunity to be there, to explain our point of view, the approach we&rsquo;re giving to Elcodi.</p>

<p>Remember, you can keep in touch with us in our <a href="https://gitter.im/elcodi/elcodi">gitter chat</a> and our <a href="https://twitter.com/elcodi_dev">twitter account</a>. Also we&rsquo;d be more than happy with more issues, PRs and collaborators in <a href="https://github.com/elcodi/elcodi">GitHub</a>… Let&rsquo;s make something funny and useful together!</p>

<p>See you in Madrid! ;&ndash;)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[A week of Elcodi #3 (10/11 - 17/11)]]></title>
    <link href="http://elcodi-blog.github.io/blog/2014/11/17/a-week-of-elcodi-number-3/"/>
    <updated>2014-11-17T17:25:20+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://elcodi-blog.github.io/blog/2014/11/17/a-week-of-elcodi-number-3</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This last week we were working hard on our next milestone: our presentation at the <a href="http://madrid2014.symfony.com">#SymfonyCon</a> on November 27th. <a href="https://github.com/mmoreram">@mmoreram</a> and <a href="https://github.com/alch">@alch</a> will speak about how we&rsquo;re building a flexible e-commerce library on top of best practices. We&rsquo;ll dig into the guts of <a href="http://elcodi.io">Elcodi</a> and talk about the tecnologies we&rsquo;ve been using to decouple and allow our users to customize everything to suit their business needs.</p>

<p>Also, @mmoream started walking this Sunday what he calls the <a href="http://mmoreram.com/blog/2014/08/07/symfony-walk-zaragoza-madrid">#SymfonyWalk</a>, a road-trip between Zaragoza and Madrid that will last for 10 days. All this on foot! We wish Marc good health and good luck in that journey!</p>

<p>In the more technical side, we&rsquo;ve been integrating <a href="https://github.com/elcodi/elcodi/tree/feature/page-component">our soon-to-be-released Elcodi&rsquo;s <code>PageBundle</code></a> into <code>bamboo-admin</code>, so you can add content pages to your stores. This will appear in the next release for sure, so… stay tuned!</p>

<p>Also, our <a href="https://github.com/hwi/HWIOAuthBundle/pull/677">PR for PayPal authentication</a> finally made it into HWI/OAuthBundle. Nice!</p>

<p>Have fun!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[A week of Elcodi #2 (3/11 - 10/11)]]></title>
    <link href="http://elcodi-blog.github.io/blog/2014/11/11/a-week-of-elcodi-number-2/"/>
    <updated>2014-11-11T12:22:31+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://elcodi-blog.github.io/blog/2014/11/11/a-week-of-elcodi-number-2</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We&rsquo;ve been putting efforts into making better issues and PRs and closing older ones for a better GitHub experience for our contributors and users.</p>

<p>The PayPal web checkout has been reintegrated into the <a href="https://github.com/elcodi/bamboo-store/pull/56">bamboo store</a> meaning that the frontend store is able to receive real payments, other than integrating a <a href="https://github.com/elcodi/bamboo-store/pull/56">dummy payment module</a> for testing purposes. Next step is to integrate <a href="https://github.com/PaymentSuite/StripeBundle">stripe</a> or <a href="https://github.com/PaymentSuite/PaymillBundle">paymill</a>, which are much more developer-friendly. Stay tuned with the <a href="https://github.com/PaymentSuite">PaymentSuite</a> updates to see what&rsquo;s coming from there too!</p>

<p>Also, there&rsquo;s a <a href="https://github.com/hwi/HWIOAuthBundle/pull/677">new PR in HWI/OAuth</a> from our team to add PayPal login support.</p>

<p>We&rsquo;ve done our first hackaton. We met with some friends to talk about the project, about our implementations and about how to approach the development of our Page Component. It has definitely been the first of many more events like this.</p>

<p>And finally, as you may know, Elcodi will speak at the <a href="http://madrid2014.symfony.com/">SymfonyCon</a> at the end of November. We will talk about some cool things we&rsquo;ve been working on during last months and since we want to celebrate this, part of the team will be walking the <em>330km route</em> between Zaragoza and Madrid. You can read more about this adventure in these posts:</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://mmoreram.com/blog/2014/08/07/symfony-walk-zaragoza-madrid/">Symfony Walk</a></li>
<li><a href="http://mmoreram.com/blog/2014/08/12/one-section-one-component/">One section, one component</a></li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[A week of Elcodi #1 (27/10 - 3/11)]]></title>
    <link href="http://elcodi-blog.github.io/blog/2014/11/04/a-week-of-elcodi-number-1/"/>
    <updated>2014-11-04T09:32:57+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://elcodi-blog.github.io/blog/2014/11/04/a-week-of-elcodi-number-1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It is time to be more vocal about what we are doing and share with the community how we are moving forward along our roadmap and the progress we are making.</p>

<p>Inspired by the <a href="http://symfony.com/blog/category/a-week-of-symfony">famous symfony weekly bulletin</a>, we would like to do something similar: <em>A week of Elcodi</em>, a series of post assembled in turn by each member of the team.</p>

<p>This week we&rsquo;ve been working on <a href="https://github.com/elcodi/bamboo-store/issues/44">social connectivity for our bamboo store</a>, allowing our users to log in from a variety of OAuth services through integration of <a href="https://github.com/hwi/HWIOAuthBundle">HWI/OAuthBundle</a> in our project.
A thin layer and a new entity <a href="https://github.com/elcodi/bamboo-store/blob/2134302656ae13768ab8e82e54053d01f105d861/src/Elcodi/StoreConnectBundle/Entity/Authorization.php#L31"><code>Authorization</code></a> stores and retrieves links between our <a href="https://github.com/elcodi/elcodi/blob/master/src/Elcodi/Component/User/Entity/Interfaces/CustomerInterface.php"><code>CustomerInterface</code></a> and the OAuth token. And voilà! You can login with your GitHub account in two clicks!</p>

<p>Sticking with our bamboo store, we prepared a feature branch with PayPal <a href="https://developer.paypal.com/docs/integration/web/web-checkout/">web checkout</a> integration. It has been developed on top of the <a href="https://github.com/PaymentSuite">PaymentSuite</a> project. You can check out the changes <a href="https://github.com/elcodi/bamboo-store/compare/features/paypal-payment?expand=1">here</a>.</p>

<p>We have also been working on a <em>Finite-state machine</em>. Until now we were managing <a href="https://github.com/elcodi/elcodi/blob/master/src/Elcodi/Component/Cart/Entity/Order.php#L38"><code>Order</code></a> and <a href="https://github.com/elcodi/elcodi/blob/master/src/Elcodi/Component/Cart/Entity/OrderLine.php#L34"><code>OrderLine</code></a> state changes using an <a href="https://github.com/elcodi/elcodi/blob/master/src/Elcodi/Component/Cart/Services/OrderStateManager.php#L28">hardwired implementation</a> which was very specific to the <code>Cart</code> component, while any logic implementing a FSM should be reusable. While waiting for Symfony to implement its own state machine in the near futire, we wrote a very simple and useful component that can be used in any project. You can check and review the <a href="https://github.com/elcodi/elcodi/pull/354">pull request</a></p>

<p>In terms of specific e-commerce features, we just merged some improvements to the Shipping component and Bundle. See the <a href="https://github.com/elcodi/elcodi/pull/309">Pull Request</a>.</p>

<p>Stay tuned!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
