<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: A week of Elcodi | Elcodi blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.elcodi.io/blog/categories/a-week-of-elcodi/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.elcodi.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-11-11T13:12:40+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.elcodi.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Elcodi Team]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[A week of Elcodi #2 (3/11 - 10/11)]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.elcodi.io/blog/2014/11/11/a-week-of-elcodi-number-2/"/>
    <updated>2014-11-11T12:22:31+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.elcodi.io/blog/2014/11/11/a-week-of-elcodi-number-2</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We&rsquo;ve been putting efforts into making better issues and PRs and closing older ones for a better GitHub experience for our contributors and users.</p>

<p>The PayPal web checkout has been reintegrated into the <a href="https://github.com/elcodi/bamboo-store/pull/56">bamboo store</a> meaning that the frontend store is able to receive real payments, other than integrating a <a href="https://github.com/elcodi/bamboo-store/pull/56">dummy payment module</a> for testing purposes. Next step is to integrate <a href="https://github.com/PaymentSuite/StripeBundle">stripe</a> or <a href="https://github.com/PaymentSuite/PaymillBundle">paymill</a>, which are much more developer-friendly. Stay tuned with the <a href="https://github.com/PaymentSuite">PaymentSuite</a> updates to see what&rsquo;s coming from there too!</p>

<p>Also, there&rsquo;s a <a href="https://github.com/hwi/HWIOAuthBundle/pull/677">new PR in HWI/OAuth</a> from our team to add PayPal login support.</p>

<p>We&rsquo;ve done our first hackaton. We met with some friends to talk about the project, about our implementations and about how to approach the development of our Page Component. It has definitely been the first of many more events like this.</p>

<p>And finally, as you may know, Elcodi will speak at the <a href="http://madrid2014.symfony.com/">SymfonyCon</a> at the end of November. We will talk about some cool things we&rsquo;ve been working on during last months and since we want to celebrate this, part of the team will be walking the <em>330km route</em> between Zaragoza and Madrid. You can read more about this adventure in these posts:</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://mmoreram.com/blog/2014/08/07/symfony-walk-zaragoza-madrid/">Symfony Walk</a></li>
<li><a href="http://mmoreram.com/blog/2014/08/12/one-section-one-component/">One section, one component</a></li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[A week of Elcodi #1 (27/10 - 3/11)]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.elcodi.io/blog/2014/11/04/a-week-of-elcodi-number-1/"/>
    <updated>2014-11-04T09:32:57+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.elcodi.io/blog/2014/11/04/a-week-of-elcodi-number-1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It is time to be more vocal about what we are doing and share with the community how we are moving forward along our roadmap and the progress we are making.</p>

<p>Inspired by the <a href="http://symfony.com/blog/category/a-week-of-symfony">famous symfony weekly bulletin</a>, we would like to do something similar: <em>A week of Elcodi</em>, a series of post assembled in turn by each member of the team.</p>

<p>This week we&rsquo;ve been working on <a href="https://github.com/elcodi/bamboo-store/issues/44">social connectivity for our bamboo store</a>, allowing our users to log in from a variety of OAuth services through integration of <a href="https://github.com/hwi/HWIOAuthBundle">HWI/OAuthBundle</a> in our project.
A thin layer and a new entity <a href="https://github.com/elcodi/bamboo-store/blob/2134302656ae13768ab8e82e54053d01f105d861/src/Elcodi/StoreConnectBundle/Entity/Authorization.php#L31"><code>Authorization</code></a> stores and retrieves links between our <a href="https://github.com/elcodi/elcodi/blob/master/src/Elcodi/Component/User/Entity/Interfaces/CustomerInterface.php"><code>CustomerInterface</code></a> and the OAuth token. And voilà! You can login with your GitHub account in two clicks!</p>

<p>Sticking with our bamboo store, we prepared a feature branch with PayPal <a href="https://developer.paypal.com/docs/integration/web/web-checkout/">web checkout</a> integration. It has been developed on top of the <a href="https://github.com/PaymentSuite">PaymentSuite</a> project. You can check out the changes <a href="https://github.com/elcodi/bamboo-store/compare/features/paypal-payment?expand=1">here</a>.</p>

<p>We have also been working on a <em>Finite-state machine</em>. Until now we were managing <a href="https://github.com/elcodi/elcodi/blob/master/src/Elcodi/Component/Cart/Entity/Order.php#L38"><code>Order</code></a> and <a href="https://github.com/elcodi/elcodi/blob/master/src/Elcodi/Component/Cart/Entity/OrderLine.php#L34"><code>OrderLine</code></a> state changes using an <a href="https://github.com/elcodi/elcodi/blob/master/src/Elcodi/Component/Cart/Services/OrderStateManager.php#L28">hardwired implementation</a> which was very specific to the <code>Cart</code> component, while any logic implementing a FSM should be reusable. While waiting for Symfony to implement its own state machine in the near futire, we wrote a very simple and useful component that can be used in any project. You can check and review the <a href="https://github.com/elcodi/elcodi/pull/354">pull request</a></p>

<p>In terms of specific e-commerce features, we just merged some improvements to the Shipping component and Bundle. See the <a href="https://github.com/elcodi/elcodi/pull/309">Pull Request</a>.</p>

<p>Stay tuned!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
