<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: release | Elcodi blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://elcodi-blog.github.io/blog/categories/release/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://elcodi-blog.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2015-11-20T22:26:47+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://elcodi-blog.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Elcodi Team]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[First stable release]]></title>
    <link href="http://elcodi-blog.github.io/blog/2015/04/04/first-stable-release/"/>
    <updated>2015-04-04T19:51:28+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://elcodi-blog.github.io/blog/2015/04/04/first-stable-release</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Hi there everyone.</p>

<p>The Elcodi core team is glad to announce that next June 1st, we will tag the
first stable release of the project (Elcodi will be still based on Symfony, you
know how much we like Symfony and its community&hellip;)</p>

<h3>Elcodi v1.0</h3>

<ul>
<li>Until this day, we&rsquo;ll finish stabilization of all packages</li>
<li>We will work so hard to finish a documentation for all of you</li>
<li>All available features will be covered by unit, functional and behavioral
tests, using PHPUnit and Behat 3.0</li>
<li>After <code>v1.0</code> we will start working on <code>v3.0</code>. This new version will be
released next November in order to be compatible with Symfony <code>v3.*</code>. It means
as well that this new version will introduce some BC Break, of course.</li>
</ul>


<p>So, we have less than 2 months to stabilize Elcodi package, and we need your
help.</p>

<p>Some days ago, we announced the
<a href="http://blog.elcodi.io/blog/2015/03/03/elcodi-bug-hunting/">Elcodi Bug Hunting</a>,
remember? Well, initially this contest was during this past March, but we have
decided to enlarge the period of the contest until June 1st, the day of the
release.</p>

<p>Until now, we have received some help from some people. Special thanks for them.</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://github.com/elcodi/elcodi/pulls?q=is%3Apr+is%3Aclosed+author%3Acordoval">cordoval</a></li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/elcodi/elcodi/pulls?q=is%3Apr+is%3Aclosed+author%3Ajaviereguiluz">javiereguiluz</a></li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/elcodi/elcodi/pulls?q=is%3Apr+is%3Aclosed+author%3Ahacfi">hacfi</a></li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/elcodi/elcodi/pulls?q=is%3Apr+is%3Aclosed+author%3Amickaelandrieu">mickaelandrieu</a></li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/elcodi/elcodi/pulls?q=is%3Apr+is%3Aclosed">And many more</a></li>
</ul>


<p>But we need some extra help in order to accomplish our goal.</p>

<h3>Win the MacBookPro</h3>

<p>Easy and super-fast. Do you want to win the MacBookPro? Easy, just help us with
some fast actions and you will be able to win the
<strong>Apple Macbook Pro 2014 Retina</strong> (of course, with an Android/Ubuntu/Windows
alternative or any geeky stuff with same price)</p>

<ul>
<li>Follow us on twitter (@elcodi_dev)</li>
<li>Give <a href="http://github.com/elcodi/elcodi">Elcodi repository</a> a star</li>
<li>Give <a href="http://github.com/elcodi/bamboo">Bamboo repository</a> a star</li>
<li>Give <a href="http://github.com/elcodi/docs">Elcodi docs repository</a> a star</li>
<li>Make a funny tweet about it, for example, sharing this post or trolling us
a little bit :)</li>
</ul>


<p>After that you will have 5 points, enough to access to the MacBookPro raffle.</p>

<h3>A little bit more&hellip;</h3>

<p>Are you interested in E-commerce and do you like Symfony? Well, there are some
extra things you can do to help. You can win the battle and win the
<strong>Ipad Air</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>[Download, install and try Bamboo)[<a href="http://elcodi.io/docs/quick-start.html">http://elcodi.io/docs/quick-start.html</a>)</li>
<li>If you find any kind of issue, please open an Issue in our repository and
report it to us.</li>
<li>Oh, you know how to fix it? That&rsquo;s wonderful! Create a Pull Request and be a
collaborator of the project!</li>
<li>We are elaborating a documentation&hellip; maybe you could help us looking for some
typo issues or creating new content&hellip;</li>
<li>Have you tried Elcodi and you want to express the world how much excited you
are? Great! Do a post in your blog and explain us what did you create with
Elcodi!</li>
<li>Elcodi is an international project, so we are looking for people able to
translate Bamboo to all languages (even in Klingon and Esperanto!). Are you
proud of your language? Well, help other people of your country for using this
project :)</li>
</ul>


<p>All this actions will give you some extra points.</p>

<p>Of course, if you need help, all Elcodi Core team will gladly help you. Just
enter <a href="https://gitter.im/elcodi/elcodi">Elcodi Gitter room</a> and say hello :)</p>

<p>Have a nice day!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
