<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: ecommerce | Elcodi blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://elcodi-blog.github.io/blog/categories/ecommerce/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://elcodi-blog.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2015-04-20T16:13:02+02:00</updated>
  <id>http://elcodi-blog.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Elcodi Team]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[First stable release]]></title>
    <link href="http://elcodi-blog.github.io/blog/2015/04/04/first-stable-release/"/>
    <updated>2015-04-04T19:51:28+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://elcodi-blog.github.io/blog/2015/04/04/first-stable-release</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Hi there everyone.</p>

<p>The Elcodi core team is glad to announce that next June 1st, we will tag the
first stable release of the project (Elcodi will be still based on Symfony, you
know how much we like Symfony and its community&hellip;)</p>

<h3>Elcodi v1.0</h3>

<ul>
<li>Until this day, we&rsquo;ll finish stabilization of all packages</li>
<li>We will work so hard to finish a documentation for all of you</li>
<li>All available features will be covered by unit, functional and behavioral
tests, using PHPUnit and Behat 3.0</li>
<li>After <code>v1.0</code> we will start working on <code>v3.0</code>. This new version will be
released next November in order to be compatible with Symfony <code>v3.*</code>. It means
as well that this new version will introduce some BC Break, of course.</li>
</ul>


<p>So, we have less than 2 months to stabilize Elcodi package, and we need your
help.</p>

<p>Some days ago, we announced the
<a href="http://blog.elcodi.io/blog/2015/03/03/elcodi-bug-hunting/">Elcodi Bug Hunting</a>,
remember? Well, initially this contest was during this past March, but we have
decided to enlarge the period of the contest until June 1st, the day of the
release.</p>

<p>Until now, we have received some help from some people. Special thanks for them.</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://github.com/elcodi/elcodi/pulls?q=is%3Apr+is%3Aclosed+author%3Acordoval">cordoval</a></li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/elcodi/elcodi/pulls?q=is%3Apr+is%3Aclosed+author%3Ajaviereguiluz">javiereguiluz</a></li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/elcodi/elcodi/pulls?q=is%3Apr+is%3Aclosed+author%3Ahacfi">hacfi</a></li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/elcodi/elcodi/pulls?q=is%3Apr+is%3Aclosed+author%3Amickaelandrieu">mickaelandrieu</a></li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/elcodi/elcodi/pulls?q=is%3Apr+is%3Aclosed">And many more</a></li>
</ul>


<p>But we need some extra help in order to accomplish our goal.</p>

<h3>Win the MacBookPro</h3>

<p>Easy and super-fast. Do you want to win the MacBookPro? Easy, just help us with
some fast actions and you will be able to win the
<strong>Apple Macbook Pro 2014 Retina</strong> (of course, with an Android/Ubuntu/Windows
alternative or any geeky stuff with same price)</p>

<ul>
<li>Follow us on twitter (@elcodi_dev)</li>
<li>Give <a href="http://github.com/elcodi/elcodi">Elcodi repository</a> a star</li>
<li>Give <a href="http://github.com/elcodi/bamboo">Bamboo repository</a> a star</li>
<li>Give <a href="http://github.com/elcodi/docs">Elcodi docs repository</a> a star</li>
<li>Make a funny tweet about it, for example, sharing this post or trolling us
a little bit :)</li>
</ul>


<p>After that you will have 5 points, enough to access to the MacBookPro raffle.</p>

<h3>A little bit more&hellip;</h3>

<p>Are you interested in E-commerce and do you like Symfony? Well, there are some
extra things you can do to help. You can win the battle and win the
<strong>Ipad Air</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>[Download, install and try Bamboo)[<a href="http://elcodi.io/docs/quick-start.html">http://elcodi.io/docs/quick-start.html</a>)</li>
<li>If you find any kind of issue, please open an Issue in our repository and
report it to us.</li>
<li>Oh, you know how to fix it? That&rsquo;s wonderful! Create a Pull Request and be a
collaborator of the project!</li>
<li>We are elaborating a documentation&hellip; maybe you could help us looking for some
typo issues or creating new content&hellip;</li>
<li>Have you tried Elcodi and you want to express the world how much excited you
are? Great! Do a post in your blog and explain us what did you create with
Elcodi!</li>
<li>Elcodi is an international project, so we are looking for people able to
translate Bamboo to all languages (even in Klingon and Esperanto!). Are you
proud of your language? Well, help other people of your country for using this
project :)</li>
</ul>


<p>All this actions will give you some extra points.</p>

<p>Of course, if you need help, all Elcodi Core team will gladly help you. Just
enter <a href="https://gitter.im/elcodi/elcodi">Elcodi Gitter room</a> and say hello :)</p>

<p>Have a nice day!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Elcodi changes its technology]]></title>
    <link href="http://elcodi-blog.github.io/blog/2015/04/01/elcodi-changes-its-technology/"/>
    <updated>2015-04-01T16:45:38+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://elcodi-blog.github.io/blog/2015/04/01/elcodi-changes-its-technology</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This is an official statement from Elcodi Team.</p>

<blockquote><p>This post was an April Fools joke. Elcodi will be based on Symfony for a long
time. We love Symfony.</p></blockquote>

<p>After some nice months using Symfony in our project Elcodi, and after many
reflections on how to increase the project quality, we&rsquo;re proud to announce that
we are moving to Ruby on Rails.</p>

<p>Until version <code>v0.6.*</code> we will continue evolving our code for these people who
is nowadays using Elcodi in their projects, but after that, we will move all
our code to Ruby.</p>

<p><img src="http://planetargon.com/images/rails-love.png" alt="We love rails" /></p>

<p>If you need some information, feel free to keep in touch with us in our
<a href="https://gitter.im/elcodi/elcodi">Gitter account</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[We have evolved]]></title>
    <link href="http://elcodi-blog.github.io/blog/2014/08/28/we-have-evolved/"/>
    <updated>2014-08-28T11:42:47+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://elcodi-blog.github.io/blog/2014/08/28/we-have-evolved</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>You might say that we&rsquo;ve evolved.</p>

<p>An evolution ought to be seen as a positive thing, and ours is no exception.
At first, we had serious doubts about the nature of our project. One of the
questions we kept asking ourselves was what factors should we consider in
choosing whether and when to engage external projects or libraries, and we
believe we made the right decision. In fact, that decision brought us forward in
a big way toward defining ourselves.</p>

<p>Flexible e-commerce components for Symfony2</p>

<p>Anyway, this phrase is actually very ambiguous, as we could be referring to
Symfony as a set of PHP components or as the Framework (I&rsquo;ve always wondered
why they have the same name&hellip; it causes a lot of confusion).</p>

<p>That&rsquo;s why we wanted to reflect a bit, starting from the code itself. Do we want
to use the Symfony Framework or the Symfony Components? The answer seemed to
emerge spontaneously. We want to work with the Symfony components, but we also
want to propose bundles that use the framework.</p>

<p>This was the origin of this commit.</p>

<p><a href="https://github.com/elcodi/elcodi/pull/239">https://github.com/elcodi/elcodi/pull/239</a></p>

<p>We have only just planted the seed with this refactoring. We have realized, even
more, the importance of having both functional testing and unit testing (unit
tests are almost all for the components, while functional tests are for the
bundles). This needs more work, but at least we have lifted this project to a
level at which we truly feel comfortable. It&rsquo;s an excellent starting point for
a long and exciting path ahead.</p>

<p>This change has resulted in some collateral damage, as it has changed the path
of our bundles, meaning that the &ldquo;subtree split&rdquo; has resulted in totally new
repositories beginning with the first commit after refactoring. This means that
all tags prior to version 0.3.0 have been lost, so we apologize to those who
have started to tinkle with our new bundles. You&rsquo;ll now need to adapt to version
~0.3 and check that everything&rsquo;s working.</p>

<p>We are available for any questions or concerns.</p>

<p>Happy coding!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Elcodi team]]></title>
    <link href="http://elcodi-blog.github.io/blog/2014/08/14/elcodi-team/"/>
    <updated>2014-08-14T10:28:08+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://elcodi-blog.github.io/blog/2014/08/14/elcodi-team</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h5>This is the follow-up of a series of posts</h5>

<ul>
<li><a href="/blog/2014/08/11/a-short-break-for-meditation/">A short break for meditation</a></li>
<li><a href="/blog/2014/08/12/our-roadmap/">Our roadmap</a>.</li>
<li><a href="/blog/2014/08/13/our-goals/">Our goals</a></li>
</ul>


<p>As a final point for what we shared in previous posts, the last but definitely not least element to consider is the <em>team</em>.</p>

<p>Such an ambitious venture needs a committed and visionary crew, and obviously more <em>heads</em> and <em>hands</em>. This is why we are opening job positions for a couple of skilled software artisans willing to join the journey with us. We will soon post the complete description. The company is located in Barcelona, Spain.</p>

<p>We are looking for passionate and inspired artisans that love to craft products to be used by fellow developers and that believe in the potential of a community that grows around an <em>opensource</em> project.</p>

<h2>Community</h2>

<p>The final word is a big <strong>thank you</strong> to all the people that have been supporting us &ndash; by contributing in different forms &ndash; and to whom will do it someday.</p>

<p>We really seek to build something useful for the community and to receive the necessary feedback and support in order to speed up the development and deliver the sound, reliable, flexible product that we have in mind.</p>

<p>As for now, the Elcodi team hopes that you&rsquo;ll get involved with the project and wishes you a great summer break.</p>

<p>Stay tuned!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Our goals]]></title>
    <link href="http://elcodi-blog.github.io/blog/2014/08/13/our-goals/"/>
    <updated>2014-08-13T10:26:56+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://elcodi-blog.github.io/blog/2014/08/13/our-goals</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h5>This is the follow-up of a series of posts</h5>

<ul>
<li><a href="/blog/2014/08/11/a-short-break-for-meditation/">A short break for meditation</a></li>
<li><a href="/blog/2014/08/12/our-roadmap/">Our roadmap</a>.</li>
</ul>


<p>In the folowing weeks we would like to get to a first community stable version. Though last week we placed the initial milestone it is important to define a release plan for the following steps.</p>

<p>We set up a list of <a href="https://github.com/elcodi/elcodi/milestones">milestones</a> to show a proposed roadmap:</p>

<p>```
Version 0.3</p>

<pre><code>- Closed 8 days ago
- 100% complete  0 open  11 closed
</code></pre>

<p>Version 0.4</p>

<pre><code>- Due by August 15, 2014
- 0% complete  0 open  0 closed
</code></pre>

<p>Version 0.5</p>

<pre><code>- Due by August 29, 2014
- 17% complete  5 open  1 closed
</code></pre>

<p>Version 0.6</p>

<pre><code>- Due by September 11, 2014
- 0% complete  2 open  0 closed
</code></pre>

<p>```</p>

<p>This means we will be working on fine-tune our general roadmap and on fixing and refining what we have &ndash; no new features will be developed until we improve stability &ndash; in the hope of clearing things up a bit for developers interested in working with Elcodi foundations.</p>

<p>At this stage, it is possible for new commits to introduce <em>BC breaks</em>. There is an open <a href="https://github.com/elcodi/elcodi/issues/34">issue</a> regarding <code>@api</code> tagging in phpdoc but as suggests in the discussion it is not really needed in the absence of a frozen stable release.</p>

<p>We won&rsquo;t be following strict <a href="http://semver.org/">semantic versioning</a> until we reach a stable release, though we are using <em>patch version</em> for small fixes that do not cause incompatibilities and <em>minor version</em> for changes that <em>could</em> cause BC.</p>

<p>Of course this will change once we approach <code>v1.0</code>, when we will <code>@api</code> freeze core components and enforce full semantic versioning.</p>

<p>Reaching the <code>stable</code> version also means we will release the <em>Market</em>, so that plugins and components can be developed with no fears of major version breaks.</p>

<p>We are on our way there, things look good!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
