<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: elcodi | Elcodi blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://elcodi-blog.github.io/blog/categories/elcodi/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://elcodi-blog.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2016-02-02T17:31:36+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://elcodi-blog.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Elcodi Team]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Purchasable Architecture]]></title>
    <link href="http://elcodi-blog.github.io/blog/2016/02/02/purchasable-architecture/"/>
    <updated>2016-02-02T16:20:49+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://elcodi-blog.github.io/blog/2016/02/02/purchasable-architecture</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It&rsquo;s been a long time since our last blog post, but we have some very good news
to share with you.</p>

<p>During the last months we&rsquo;ve been working on new projects for Elcodi. Some of
them are not available yet, but some of them have been merged recently. This
post is basically to show you what has changed and improved in Elcodi and to
spread the word about our new Roadmap for the next months. This roadmap is
exactly the same one, but with different dates due to these new changes.</p>

<h3>Purchasable</h3>

<p>From almost the beginning of the life of our project, and because the entity
product and related ones are one of the main topic of all e-commerce projects,
we have tried to manage how abstract should be all this entity family. For
example, should we create a Purchasable interface to be used in Cart and Order?
Should we use only one entity to manage all kind of purchasable entities? Should
we use traits for that? How many interfaces?</p>

<p>Like all software projects, this is a question that can be solved in several
ways. One of these ways is analyzing our needs and creating a software model
from these needs. Of course, this is the right way if you have time, money and
resources. Another way is just by trying one approach. Working with it, dealing
with it as much as possible, and listening yourself, looking for your needs.
This approach needs time, only time, and the capacity of refactoring, of action,
of change.</p>

<p>Well. This one, the last one, is the approach we&rsquo;ve used some time ago. At the
beginning, using two entities, Product and Variant, to define both purchasable
types has been a good choice. And it&rsquo;s been like this until now. Since some
months ago, one of the most asked questions have been&hellip; <em>well, how can I create
my own purchasable?</em>, and with this approach, was not simple, was not logical.</p>

<p>Well. We have reacted and a new Purchasable implementation is here.</p>

<p>Instead of dealing with products and variants, Elcodi&rsquo;s cart is going to deal
only with purchasable implementations. We&rsquo;ve started using Doctrine CTI (Class
Table Inheritance) to allow other implementation coexist with current ones, so
if you need to work with your own purchasable implementation&hellip; just create it,
implement this interface and it&rsquo;s done :)</p>

<p>That simple!</p>

<h3>Elcodi v2.0.0</h3>

<p>Our Roadmap was clear. Elcodi <em>v1.1.0</em> had to be tagged the first of January,
but we really wanted this feature to be available and in master as soon as
possible.</p>

<p>A change like that can needs a major version change, and even we know that is
too soon to create a new major version, we think that this is the best for the
project and the best for our evolution.</p>

<p>We are not specialists in maintaining several branches at all, so we will not
support versions <em>v1.0</em> actively. What we will do for sure is supporting somehow
all projects that want to go from <em>v1.0</em> to <em>v2.0</em>. At this moment we don&rsquo;t have
any tool for that but, if there are some requests, we will do it for sure.</p>

<p>So, if you need us, just <a href="http://gitter.im/elcodi/elcodi">Ask for help</a></p>

<h3>New Roadmap</h3>

<p>Of course our roadmap has changed, but only with dates.<br/>
Let&rsquo;s take a look at the new plan.</p>

<h4>v2.1</h4>

<ul>
<li>Released the 1st of June, 2016</li>
<li>Search engine using ElasticSearch will be introduced here</li>
<li>Product API will be added</li>
<li>User API will be added</li>
<li>Cart API will be added</li>
<li>Some Media improvements, like new media types</li>
<li>New shop template will be added</li>
<li>Back panel documentation</li>
<li>Code Coverage of all components and bundles over 60%</li>
<li>Templates documentation</li>
</ul>


<h4>v2.2</h4>

<ul>
<li>Released the 1st of September, 2016</li>
<li>Multistore. Switch between stores in the same installation</li>
<li>Shop API will be added</li>
<li>New shop template will be added</li>
<li>New tempates and plugins website with tons of cool new stuff for all Elcodi and Bamboo implementations</li>
<li>Code Coverage of all components and bundles over 70%</li>
</ul>


<h4>v2.3</h4>

<ul>
<li>Released the 1st of January, 2017</li>
<li>We will remove all deprecated code</li>
<li>Bamboo will use Symfony3 and maybe new version of Doctrine</li>
<li>Updated all dependencies</li>
<li>Marketplace</li>
<li>Elcodi community site will be created.</li>
<li>Unknown bunch of new and cool stuff</li>
<li>Code Coverage of all components and bundles over 80%</li>
</ul>


<h3>Try us</h3>

<p>You can start using Elcodi in a very very fast way, just&hellip; DO IT!</p>

<p><a href="http://elcodi.io/docs/quick-start/">Install Elcodi</a></p>

<h3>Last thoughts</h3>

<p>Well, Elcodi project is keep doing. Remember that we need a lot of help, and we
really want you to test our project, take a small tour around what we offer and
if you like, only if you like&hellip;</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://github.com/elcodi/elcodi">Star us</a></li>
<li><a href="https://gitter.com/elcodi/elcodi">Join us</a></li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/elcodi/elcodi/issues">Help us</a></li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Suggest our next features]]></title>
    <link href="http://elcodi-blog.github.io/blog/2015/11/23/suggest-our-next-features/"/>
    <updated>2015-11-23T17:13:35+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://elcodi-blog.github.io/blog/2015/11/23/suggest-our-next-features</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>For sure some of you already know about
<a href="http://blog.elcodi.io/blog/2015/11/20/elcodi-online-meetup/">Elcodi&rsquo;s first online meetup</a>.
It will be next November 25th at 6:00pm GMT+1, and for joining us, you only have
to enter <a href="http://gitter.im/elcodi/elcodi">our gitter room</a>, say hello, and join
our discussion about Elcodi, Symfony and E-commerce.</p>

<p>One of the topics we&rsquo;ll talk about will be our roadmap. We&rsquo;ve configured it just
by thinking what features would be nice to have in the <del>future</del> present, but
Elcodi is a community-first project, so we would love to bring you some voice,
at least to help us deciding about what features we should put our effort the
next months.</p>

<blockquote><p>Of course, your voice is the most wanted voice in Elcodi. Make sure you really
say what you think, so we can improve day by day.</p></blockquote>

<p>For that, from today until the start of the meeting, you will be able to join
our room and show us your proposals. This wednesday we will vote each one, and
the most voted will be part of our <code>v1.3</code> roadmap, creating a group of
volunteers for that development.</p>

<h3>Propose a feature</h3>

<ul>
<li>Enter <a href="http://gitter.im/elcodi/elcodi">our gitter room</a></li>
<li>Say Hello! :)</li>
<li>Make a proposal</li>
</ul>


<h3>Vote the features</h3>

<ul>
<li>Enter <a href="http://gitter.im/elcodi/elcodi">our gitter room</a> next November 25th at
6:00pm GMT+1</li>
<li>Say hello! :)</li>
<li>Vote your more exciting features (before starting the meetup, you will have
the link for voting)</li>
<li>Join the development!</li>
<li>Enjoy as much as possible ;)</li>
</ul>


<p>We really look forward to see you all there!
By sharing this post you will really help us creating this community :)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Elcodi online meetup]]></title>
    <link href="http://elcodi-blog.github.io/blog/2015/11/20/elcodi-online-meetup/"/>
    <updated>2015-11-20T21:50:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://elcodi-blog.github.io/blog/2015/11/20/elcodi-online-meetup</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://elcodi.io">Elcodi</a> is growing so fast.</p>

<blockquote><p>Elcodi is an E-commerce platform based on Symfony components. Is composed by
some PHP Components, by some Symfony Bundles and by a Full-stack project based
on the Symfony Framework. A all-in-one E-commerce solution, splitted in
several isolated parts.</p></blockquote>

<p>We started this project two and a half years ago, and our community is getting
bigger day after day. That&rsquo;s great because the project grows as well as long as
more people start using it (more needs, more ideas, more contributions, more
fun).</p>

<p>We will start doing monthly meetings online in our
<a href="http://gitter.im/elcodi/elcodi">Gitter channel</a>. Right now, some people is
daily contributing to Elcodi and having some nice and constructive talks, but we
want to make it even bigger.</p>

<p>Our first monthly meeting will be next November 25th at 6:00pm GMT+1.
This meeting will be hosted by the core team of the project,
<a href="https://github.com/mmoreram">Marc Morera</a> and
<a href="https://github.com/EmanueleMinotto">Emanuele Minotto</a>.</p>

<h2>Agenda</h2>

<p>This meeting will be focused on creating some working groups for the next weeks.
Depending on the people attending at the meeting, we will create more or less
groups, focused on some parts of the application.</p>

<p>These are the points we will talk about.</p>

<ul>
<li>Tasks for next version <code>v1.1</code>.</li>
<li>Documentation update and revision.</li>
<li>Test coverage for <code>v1.1</code>.</li>
<li>Community action. How to make as many people as possible involved.</li>
</ul>


<h2>Attendees</h2>

<p>Maybe you&rsquo;re asking yourself if this meeting is for you.</p>

<p>Well, it depends on your interests. If your job is all about E-commerce, even if
your Symfony skills are no so good, then you should join us. You will have the
opportunity to share some time with really skilled people and to know the way we
have created this project.</p>

<p>If your interest is open source, join us as well. Elcodi is a young project,
focused on finding the right equilibrium between pragmatism and clean
architecture. We use Event-Driven Architecture and annotations at the same time.
Do you want to know why? What are our thoughts? Ask us :)</p>

<p>In other words, if you want to have a nice time with some really good people,
then you definitely should join us and say a big Hello!</p>

<p>Remember, next November 25th at&hellip;</p>

<ul>
<li>Mexico City, La Havana &ndash; 11:00am</li>
<li>London &ndash; 05:00pm</li>
<li>Barcelona, Paris, Warsaw &ndash; 06:00pm</li>
<li>Moscow &ndash; 08:00pm</li>
</ul>


<p>Looking forward to see you all there!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Meet Deliberry]]></title>
    <link href="http://elcodi-blog.github.io/blog/2015/10/19/meet-deliberry/"/>
    <updated>2015-10-19T17:53:22+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://elcodi-blog.github.io/blog/2015/10/19/meet-deliberry</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>As an open source project, whenever a project touches success using our
technology, our pride feelings are indescribable. Each project based on Elcodi
means a different and unique story for us. Each one as much important as the
best.</p>

<p>But in this case, we want to talk about one of our first projects using Elcodi
as the main technology. And we want to do that because we really love this
company, and the way they want to really change the world. Like we want.</p>

<p>The name of the project is <a href="http://deliberry.com">Deliberry</a>, and they are
placed in Barcelona.</p>

<p><img src="http://elcodi.io/img/showcase/deliberry.png" alt="Deliberry" /></p>

<p>They deliver your supermarket purchases in less than one hour. This is great,
right? They used Elcodi components as the main technology, and our Bamboo
project as the basis for their front engine and their admin site.</p>

<p>They started using Elcodi some months ago, when we were working on version
<code>v0.5.0</code>. These days, Elcodi was very unstable, so day after day, we introduced
new changes, affecting strongly the BC standard. Even with that scenario,
Deliberry has been always our first tester for new versions, working side by
side with us, and reporting us as many issues as possible.</p>

<p>And believe us&hellip; For a new open source project&hellip; this is the best gift we&rsquo;ve
had.</p>

<h2>Changing the world with us</h2>

<p>One of the biggest things that makes this project really awesome, is that they
are really changing the world.</p>

<p>We are very used of thinking that, for a company than simply delivers food,
changing the world means delivering it faster and better. Of course, this is
great, but your are only changing part of the world, and probably, the part than
less need a change.</p>

<p>Deliberry works side by side with an organization name
<a href="http://www.caritas.es/">Cáritas</a>. This organization helps people suffering of
social exclusion (yes, in Spain we have a lot of this, sadly). People without
many resources, that cannot enjoy whether the purchase is fast or not: they
cannot even buy anything.</p>

<p>Deliberry help this organization by hiring people from this organization for
buying people&rsquo;s food, or delivering it. And everything, in less than one hour.</p>

<p>Isn&rsquo;t it fantastic?</p>

<p><a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=6sXPaFB93is" title="Deliberry TV1"><img src="http://img.youtube.com/vi/6sXPaFB93is/0.jpg" alt="Deliberry TV1" /></a></p>

<p>Deliberry is our hero. Thanks for being part of the Elcodi history, and keep
changing the world, we will try to do the same :)</p>

<h2>Try Deliberry</h2>

<p>At the moment, Deliberry is only working on Barcelona, but if you are living
here, we encourage you to try it. And even better, we want to give you a nice
discount for your next purchase.</p>

<p>Use the discount code <strong><em>ELCODI</em></strong>, and with a minimum purchase of 40€ you will
recieve 10€ of discount. And if is your first time, the delivery fees will be
free!</p>

<p>Hurry up! You can use this discount during this year :)</p>

<h2>Change the world too</h2>

<p>We are looking for projects that want to change the world, somehow, somewhere.
If you have in mind one of them, consider the usage of Elcodi. Our biggest
effort goes to providing happiness and joy between E-commerce developers,
mastering amazing projects full of creativity and innovation.</p>

<p>Only this scenario turns on the best projects ever, and only the best projects
ever can change this world.</p>

<p>So&hellip; we are looking for you.<br/>
<a href="http://elcodi.io">Join us!</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Install Elcodi]]></title>
    <link href="http://elcodi-blog.github.io/blog/2015/07/07/install-elcodi/"/>
    <updated>2015-07-07T12:59:39+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://elcodi-blog.github.io/blog/2015/07/07/install-elcodi</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In order to decrease the time of installation of Elcodi, and with our new Beta
release</p>

<p><a href="https://github.com/elcodi/bamboo/blob/master/CHANGELOG-1.0.md#v100-beta3-10-07-2015">Bamboo v1.0.0-beta3</a><br/>
<a href="https://github.com/elcodi/elcodi/blob/master/CHANGELOG-1.0.md#v100-beta3-10-07-2015">Elcodi v1.0.0-beta3</a></p>

<p>we&rsquo;ve been working on how fast you can create a new shop in your localhost and
start tuning it. It is important right?</p>

<h2>New elcodi:install command</h2>

<p>Elcodi is Symfony based. This means that to make it work you need to execute
some commands in order to do some common actions (create database, update
schema, populate fixtures&hellip;)</p>

<p>To improve this step, we have created a new console command in order to decrease
this installation time and the number of steps required to play with your
localhost.</p>

<p>4 steps to rule them all, and less than 3 minutes to start with Elcodi.</p>

<p><code>bash
$ curl -s http://getcomposer.org/installer | php
$ php composer.phar create-project elcodi/bamboo bamboo -sdev
$ cd bamboo/
$ php app/console elcodi:install
</code></p>

<p>As soon as Bamboo is installed, you can create a temporary server by using the
PHP built-in server</p>

<p><code>bash
$ php app/console server:run
</code></p>

<p>And check your Bamboo installation in your browser by accessing to
<code>http://localhost:8000</code>.</p>

<h2>GD instead of ImageMagick</h2>

<p>Because we have implemented some needs using adapters, we have implemented a new
image resize adapter based on the PHP GD engine. The good thing is that GD is
already installed in all standard PHP versions, so you don&rsquo;t really need to
install any extra library.</p>

<p>This new adapter has been proposed and accepted as the default one, and of
course, ImageMagick adapter can be still used by changing the configuration
value.</p>

<p>``` yml
elcodi_media:</p>

<pre><code>images:
    resize:
        adapter: elcodi.media_resize.imagemagick
</code></pre>

<p>```</p>

<h2>Location repository</h2>

<p>In Elcodi you can populate new countries. With this new installation command,
and by using <code>--country</code> option, you can add already generated countries in
seconds. You can see available pregenerated countries in our
<a href="https://github.com/elcodi/LocationDumps">LocationDumps</a> repository. We will
generate all countries over time.</p>

<blockquote><p>If you want to use the demo application, make sure you install Spain. All
already built addresses are from Spain. Otherwise, feel free to build your
Location database as you need.</p></blockquote>

<p>Imagine you want to install France and Italy. Well, you should do that</p>

<p><code>bash
$ php app/console elcodi:install --country=FR --country=IT
</code></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
