<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: beta | Elcodi blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://elcodi-blog.github.io/blog/categories/beta/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://elcodi-blog.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2015-11-20T22:26:47+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://elcodi-blog.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Elcodi Team]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Elcodi beta is here]]></title>
    <link href="http://elcodi-blog.github.io/blog/2015/06/18/elcodi-beta-is-here/"/>
    <updated>2015-06-18T13:42:16+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://elcodi-blog.github.io/blog/2015/06/18/elcodi-beta-is-here</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>&hellip; and we did it.</p>

<p>It is something really amazing. We&rsquo;ve finally reached our first Beta stage.
After more than 1 year of hard and non-stop work, we have tagged our first beta
version in order to provide some stability to all Elcodi installations.</p>

<h2>What means Beta</h2>

<p>If you read some literature about software versions, you&rsquo;ll find that there is
always a set of pre-defined steps based on the stability of the project</p>

<ul>
<li>v1.0.0-alpha1: Hey developer! We&rsquo;re building it but we&rsquo;re not ready to be used
in production. Possible big BC breaks, incremental set of features and less
communication. Careful!</li>
<li>v1.0.0-beta1: Hey developer! Well, we think that we&rsquo;re done. We think that
we&rsquo;re done with features so we aim to stabilize the version. Testing and
documentation is part of the development here. C'mon!</li>
<li>v1.0.0-RC1: Hey developer! Tested enough, so&hellip; how about make this package
stable? Lets purpose a set of BC promises and let&rsquo;s make possible the usage of
<code>^1.0</code> in composer.</li>
<li>v1.0.0: Hey everyone! We&rsquo;re here! This package is stable. We think that we&rsquo;ve
no many issues here, so don&rsquo;t hesitate to using us in your projects.</li>
</ul>


<p>Of course, some people or projects will understand these steps in a different
way, but in Elcodi, this is the idea.</p>

<h2>Communication</h2>

<p>For the last months, we have been focused on developing.</p>

<ul>
<li>elcodi/elcodi

<ul>
<li>1.616 commits</li>
<li>239 Issues closed</li>
<li>586 PR accepted</li>
<li>21 Contributors</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>elcodi/bamboo

<ul>
<li>1.763 commits</li>
<li>49 Issues closed</li>
<li>450 PR accepted</li>
<li>21 Contributors</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<p>Of course, developing have been our priority and we&rsquo;ve lost the opportunity of
showing the world our great work. Our communication has been poor and
insufficient because of our lack of time. And we know that this aspect of the
project need to change.</p>

<p>Since today, we&rsquo;ll return with our &ldquo;A week of Elcodi&rdquo;. Each week we will
document all our work. Each project using Elcodi will have a lot of feedback.
Each change affecting the BC compatibility will be announced in a properly way
and since today, we will take care about all projects by creating and promoting
our own community events and User Groups around the world.</p>

<p>Remember all the core team is in <a href="https://gitter.im/elcodi/elcodi">Gitter</a> so if
you have doubts and you want to talk about any aspect of the project, don&rsquo;t
hesitate to talk with us :)</p>

<p>Follow us on <a href="https://twitter.com/elcodi_dev">Twitter</a> to join us!</p>

<h2>Reaching RC</h2>

<p>We&rsquo;re done with features. We have developed a nice Plugin infrastructure that
will be documented as soon as possible, in order to externalize all extra
implementations. Our maximum priority right now is to finish what we begin
one year ago.</p>

<p>The project is pretty stable, being used in some projects in production, selling
and working properly. For example <a href="http://deliberry.com">deliberry.com</a>, a
company based in Barcelona that is actually growing day by day, based in Elcodi.</p>

<p>We&rsquo;re proud!</p>

<blockquote><p>We&rsquo;ll have soon a great directory with projects based on Elcodi, so if your
company is Elcodi based, please, show us your case :)</p></blockquote>

<p>So, for the next 2 months, we will support all projects based on Elcodi, with
a big testing layer with more Unit, Functional, Behavioral and Response testing.</p>

<p>We will add tons of documentation showing how to do every single thing inside
the Elcodi world and finally, as soon Elcodi is stable enough, then we will
tag the first RC version.</p>

<h2>Test us!</h2>

<p>We are Open Source, and supporting us will never mean paying us. Elcodi is free
because is born from and for the community, so the best way to promote Elcodi is
talking about it.</p>

<p>Elcodi is not only E-commerce and Symfony, is about developing, sharing,
enjoying and improving. Each member of the community is important and we will
demonstrate this not only with words but with a strong layer of support.</p>

<p>As soon as the community will grow, we will lead the creation of user groups
around the world. We will show how we work and what using Elcodi is not only an
experience but a way of understanding the E-commerce development.</p>

<p><a href="http://elcodi.io/docs/quick-start/">Test us now</a> and share your thoughts, your
non-valuable feedback, or <a href="https://gitter.im/elcodi/elcodi">just say hello</a> :)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
