<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: install | Elcodi blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://elcodi-blog.github.io/blog/categories/install/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://elcodi-blog.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2015-11-23T17:48:10+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://elcodi-blog.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Elcodi Team]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Install Elcodi]]></title>
    <link href="http://elcodi-blog.github.io/blog/2015/07/07/install-elcodi/"/>
    <updated>2015-07-07T12:59:39+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://elcodi-blog.github.io/blog/2015/07/07/install-elcodi</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In order to decrease the time of installation of Elcodi, and with our new Beta
release</p>

<p><a href="https://github.com/elcodi/bamboo/blob/master/CHANGELOG-1.0.md#v100-beta3-10-07-2015">Bamboo v1.0.0-beta3</a><br/>
<a href="https://github.com/elcodi/elcodi/blob/master/CHANGELOG-1.0.md#v100-beta3-10-07-2015">Elcodi v1.0.0-beta3</a></p>

<p>we&rsquo;ve been working on how fast you can create a new shop in your localhost and
start tuning it. It is important right?</p>

<h2>New elcodi:install command</h2>

<p>Elcodi is Symfony based. This means that to make it work you need to execute
some commands in order to do some common actions (create database, update
schema, populate fixtures&hellip;)</p>

<p>To improve this step, we have created a new console command in order to decrease
this installation time and the number of steps required to play with your
localhost.</p>

<p>4 steps to rule them all, and less than 3 minutes to start with Elcodi.</p>

<p><code>bash
$ curl -s http://getcomposer.org/installer | php
$ php composer.phar create-project elcodi/bamboo bamboo -sdev
$ cd bamboo/
$ php app/console elcodi:install
</code></p>

<p>As soon as Bamboo is installed, you can create a temporary server by using the
PHP built-in server</p>

<p><code>bash
$ php app/console server:run
</code></p>

<p>And check your Bamboo installation in your browser by accessing to
<code>http://localhost:8000</code>.</p>

<h2>GD instead of ImageMagick</h2>

<p>Because we have implemented some needs using adapters, we have implemented a new
image resize adapter based on the PHP GD engine. The good thing is that GD is
already installed in all standard PHP versions, so you don&rsquo;t really need to
install any extra library.</p>

<p>This new adapter has been proposed and accepted as the default one, and of
course, ImageMagick adapter can be still used by changing the configuration
value.</p>

<p>``` yml
elcodi_media:</p>

<pre><code>images:
    resize:
        adapter: elcodi.media_resize.imagemagick
</code></pre>

<p>```</p>

<h2>Location repository</h2>

<p>In Elcodi you can populate new countries. With this new installation command,
and by using <code>--country</code> option, you can add already generated countries in
seconds. You can see available pregenerated countries in our
<a href="https://github.com/elcodi/LocationDumps">LocationDumps</a> repository. We will
generate all countries over time.</p>

<blockquote><p>If you want to use the demo application, make sure you install Spain. All
already built addresses are from Spain. Otherwise, feel free to build your
Location database as you need.</p></blockquote>

<p>Imagine you want to install France and Italy. Well, you should do that</p>

<p><code>bash
$ php app/console elcodi:install --country=FR --country=IT
</code></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
